Hello English learners. Welcome back to
English Pod. My name is Marco and I'm Erica
and today we're going to be talking about
a really common situation with parents.
Yeah, when you're a teenager you
always need to ask your parents for money.
Ask your parents for the car or ask
your parents if you can do something.
Exactly and that's what
we're going to be looking at is
how you can ask for
permission for the car for money.
Right and these phrases are
not only for your parents, right?
No, you could use them in
your office, with your boss
or for any situation where
you need to ask politely.
Okay, so let's take a look
at vocabulary preview.
Very cabaret-y preview.
We have one word for you today.
Concerts.
A concert.
A concert is an event, right?
Yeah.
Where people play music.
Right.
So you have different types
of concerts like a rock concert.
They play rock music or a pop concert.
Yeah, a pop music or even
a classical music concert.
Exactly where you have people
playing violins and pianos.
Yeah.
Okay, concert.
So concerts are always for music.
Yeah, exactly. They're always for music.
Well, with that, let's
go into our dialogue.
Marco, what happens here?
Well, basically we have a
teenage girl who needs to
go to a concert and is
asking her dad for something.
All right, let's listen.
Hey, Daddy.
You look great today.
I like your tie.
By the way, I was wondering, can I?
No.
Haven't even told you what it is yet.
Okay, okay.
What do you want?
Do you think I could borrow the car?
I'm going to a concert tonight.
Um, I don't think so.
I need the car tonight
to pick up your mother.
Oh, I told you about it last week.
Smelly toes is playing, and
Eric asked if I would go with him.
Who is this Eric guy?
duh.
He's like the hottest and
most popular guy at school.
Come on, Dad.
Please.
No can't do.
Sorry.
Fine, then.
Would you mind giving me 100 bucks?
No way.
Oh, that's so unfair.
Teenagers, huh?
Yeah.
They're always asking for something.
Yeah, this brings back memories,
but I'll tell you about that later.
Why don't we take a look at the
vocabulary in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
All right, we've got a few
interesting words here.
Um, the first one, hottest.
Hotest.
So this is the superlative of hot.
Right.
So the hottest guy in
school is the most handsome.
Yeah, the most sexy guy in school.
Exactly.
So if somebody is hot,
they are really attractive.
Really good looking.
Um, and so Marco, is this a
word that is only used for men?
No, it's you can also use it for women.
Um, and what about things?
You know, recently with
Paris Hilton, it's more
popular with things
like, wow, I got a new car.
Wow, that's hot.
Right.
Um, but I guess we maybe should tell
our listeners to be careful with this word.
Yeah, you don't really want
to tell somebody you're hot.
No, it's not very polite.
But with your friends,
you can use this word.
Exactly.
If I'm talking with my friends
and I see a girl like, wow, she's hot.
Okay.
But just don't tell her.
Yeah, don't go up to her
and say, wow, you're hot.
Okay.
Our next word, most popular.
Most popular.
Another superlative.
Exactly.
And popular means,
means having a lot of friends.
Exactly.
Having a lot of friends
or being well known.
Or well liked.
Well liked.
Yep.
So in every school,
there's always like the
most popular guy in
school, the most popular girl.
Yep.
Were you the most popular guy?
Um, not really.
No, I wasn't the most popular
guy, but I wasn't unpopular.
Okay.
So that's the opposite.
Yeah.
So that was, I was okay.
All right.
Our last phrase.
Find then.
Well, this is a phrase
made up of two simple
words, but why don't we
listen to some examples
so we can understand the
meaning of these two words together.
Example one.
Find then.
If you won't go with me, I'll go by myself.
Example two.
Find then.
If you want to break up, I don't care.
Example three.
You want to go out with your friends?
Find then.
Go.
So you would use this
when you agree with
somebody, but you're
not really happy about it.
Yeah.
It's like saying I agree,
but I'm really angry.
Right.
Maybe sometimes because
you don't have a choice.
Yeah.
Right.
Like the girl.
Find then.
Yeah.
So even though we have
the word fine in there,
it's not really a nice
thing to say to someone.
No, no, this is definitely not
one to use with your boss.
Right.
Yeah.
Exactly.
Okay.
And then we'll talk
about some more phrases.
Hey, Daddy.
You look great today.
I like your tie.
By the way, I was wondering, can I?
No.
I haven't even told you what it is yet.
Okay.
What do you want?
Do you think I could borrow the car?
I'm going to a concert tonight.
Hmm.
I don't think so.
I need the car tonight
to pick up your mother.
Ugh.
I told you about it last week.
Smelly toes is playing.
And Eric asked if I would go with him.
Who is this Eric guy?
Duh.
He's like the hottest and
most popular guy at school.
Come on, Dad.
Please.
No can do.
Sorry.
Fine, then.
Would you mind giving me 100 bucks?
No way.
That's so unfair.
There's a lot of
phrases in this dialogue
that we can use to ask
for something, right?
Exactly.
And in a very polite way.
Okay.
So we're going to look at three
ways of asking for something.
And the first way is I was wondering.
I was wondering.
So I could say I was wondering,
can I borrow your car?
Yeah.
Or I was wondering,
can I stay at your house?
Okay.
It's a very nice way to ask something.
Yeah.
It's like to begin a question.
To begin, yeah.
All right.
Let's take a look at the next one.
And it's basically the same thing.
Do you think I could?
Do you think I could borrow the car?
Yeah.
Do you think I could use your computer?
I can say I was wondering,
can I use your computer?
Do you think I could use your computer?
Yeah.
They mean the same.
Right.
Now let's look at the last one.
Would you mind?
So I could say, would you
mind holding this for me?
Yep.
Or would you mind
finishing this report for me?
Now there's an interesting thing here that
you have the verb in a gerund form, right?
Right.
The ING form.
Exactly.
Giving, holding, finishing.
So we've got, I was
wondering, can I do something?
Right.
And would you mind doing something?
Yeah.
So you have the ING.
Mm-hmm.
Be very, very careful.
Be sure to not say, would
you mind to give me?
Right.
That's wrong.
Let's say, would you mind giving me?
Yep.
Okay.
Let's listen to some more
examples of these three phrases.
Example one.
Would you mind cooking dinner tonight?
I'll be home late.
Example two.
We were wondering if you
could buy the tickets for us?
Example three.
Do you think you can have
those reports finished by today?
All right.
So I think it's really clear now.
Yeah.
And it's a very useful
way of asking for things.
Okay.
So let's listen to our
dialogue for the third time.
And then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more.
Hey, Daddy.
You look great today.
I like your tie.
By the way, I was wondering, can I?
No.
Haven't even told you what it is yet.
Okay.
What do you want?
Do you think I could borrow the car?
I'm going to a concert tonight.
Um, I don't think so.
I need the car tonight
to pick up your mother.
Oh, I told you about it last week.
Smelly toes is playing.
And Eric asked if I would go with him.
Who is this Eric guy?
duh.
He's like the hottest and
most popular guy at school.
Come on, Dad.
Please.
No can't do.
Sorry.
Fine then.
Would you mind giving me 100 bucks?
No way.
Oh, that's so unfair.
So Marco, you said that this dialogue
really brought back some memories for you.
Yeah.
My dad was exactly the same way.
I would just say dad and
he would be like, no, so
he would always cut me
off before I ask anything.
Uh, sounds like a pretty strict guy.
No, but it was a lot of fun.
Sometimes he would just say it just to
make me angry or something like that.
It was a joke.
Yeah, exactly.
But it was difficult to get him
to lend me the car, for example.
Really?
Oh, yeah.
I mean, he wouldn't just lend me the car.
And sometimes if he
did lend me the car, then
the next day, he would be like, a, you need
to wash the car or something like that.
So there's, so you had to pay him back.
I had to pay him back with something.
In my family, I was
always allowed to borrow
the car because we lived really,
really far away from the city.
So there were no buses or subway,
but I always got to borrow the worst car.
You know, the most terrible car.
Oh, really?
Which led to so many problems.
Like my car stopping working in the
middle of the street, which was never good.
We did use to live a
little bit further away
from downtown, but we
had a good bus system.
Yep.
So it'd just be like, take the
bus is cheaper and stuff like that.
So I didn't really get
the car that often until
I bought my own or until I had a motorcycle
of my own and then problem solved.
All right.
Well, I want to know from our listeners,
what did they ask for from their parents?
Exactly.
Did you ask for the car?
Did you ask for money?
Or did you ask for a pony?
Did you ask for a pony?
I had a friend who had a summer home.
Really?
So he would ask for the
keys to the summer home.
Okay.
Well, come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
Exactly.
Leave your questions and comments.
We want to hear from you.
We want to know what you think.
Eric and I are definitely
there to answer any doubts.
All right.
Well, guys, thanks for listening.
And until next time, bye.